He used to say the river remembers
everything you throw into it.
[Rain on stone. Water moving.]
There are things that take years to reach you.
He left in November.
The grief arrived in March.
[Bridge. River swollen below.
Wind. A truck passes.]
I keep thinking I see him.
Not as a ghost. Just -- in the way
a room holds the shape of someone
who used to fill it.
[Group murmur. Rain outside.
Folding chairs.]
It's not that I want him back.
I know that's not possible.
It's that I want to stop
being surprised that he's gone.
[River at night. Moonlight
on the water. Complete silence.]
I brought his photograph here every week
for three months.
Tonight I brought the box.
I don't know what that means yet.
[She does not throw it in.
She sits with it.]
[Spring. Morning light.
Tall grass. She walks.]
[She does not look back.]
[Silence. Then: birdsong.
Wind in the grass.]